<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Welcome to HiveMind</title>
        <author email="jkuhnert@apache.org">Jesse Kuhnert</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Welcome to HiveMind">
            <strong>
                <a href="#Third Party Components">Third Party Components</a> -- <a href="#HiveMind Extensions">Third
                    Party Extensions</a> -- <a href="#IDE Integration">IDE Integration</a>
            </strong>

            <br/>

            <div id="downloadbox">
                <h5>Get HiveMind 1.1.1</h5>
                <p>
                    <a href="download.html">
                        <img valign="top" src="images/folder-open.gif" border="0" alt="" title="download"/> Download
                    </a> HiveMind 1.1.1 </p>

                <br/>


                <!-- Leave the last few news items here -->

                <h5>New!</h5>
                <ul style="list-style:none">
                    <li><a href="news.html#Jumpstart 0.8">Jumpstart v0.8 released</a></li>
                    <li><a href="news.html#Enjoying Web Development with HiveMind updated for T4.1"> EWDT updated for T4.1</a></li>
                    <li><a href="news.html#HandyHiveMind, IntelliJ Plugin"> HandyHiveMind IntelliJ Plugin</a></li>
                    <li><a href="news.html#HiveMind 101 book released"> HiveMind 101 book released </a></li>
                    <li><a href="news.html#HiveMind NetBeans interview"> HiveMind NetBeans interview </a></li>
                </ul>
                
            </div>
            <p> HiveMind is an open-source framework for creating dynamic, robust, highly scalable web applications in
                Java. HiveMind complements and builds upon the standard Java Servlet API, and so it works in any servlet
                container or application server. </p>
            <p> HiveMind divides a web application into a set of pages, each constructed from components. This provides
                a consistent structure, allowing the HiveMind framework to assume responsibility for key concerns such
                as URL construction and dispatch, persistent state storage on the client or on the server, user input
                validation, localization/internationalization, and exception reporting. Developing HiveMind applications
                involves creating HTML templates using plain HTML, and combining the templates with small amounts of
                Java code using (optional) XML descriptor files. In HiveMind, you create your application in terms of
                objects, and the methods and properties of those objects -- and specifically not in terms of URLs and
                query parameters. HiveMind brings true object oriented development to Java web applications. </p>
            <p> HiveMind is specifically designed to make creating new components very easy, as this is a routine
                approach when building applications. The distribution includes over fifty components, ranging from
                simple output components all the way up to complex data grids and tree navigators. </p>
            <p> HiveMind is architected to scale from tiny applications all the way up to massive applications
                consisting of hundreds of individual pages, developed by large, diverse teams. HiveMind easily
                integrates with any kind of backend, including J2EE, HiveMind and Spring. </p>
            <p>HiveMind is released under the Apache Software Licence 2.0.</p>
            <p>
                <h4>Key Principles</h4>
            </p>
            <p>HiveMind is organized around four key principles:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <b>Simplicity</b> - web applications shouldn't be rocket science! </li>
                <li>
                    <b>Consistency</b> - what works in pages should work in components. What works in small applications
                    should work in large applications. Different developers should find similar solutions to similar
                    problems. </li>
                <li>
                    <b>Efficiency</b> - applications should be performant and scalable </li>
                <li>
                    <b>Feedback</b> - when things go wrong, the framework should not get in the way; in fact, it should
                    provide useful diagnostics </li>
            </ul>
            <p> These four principles drive the meta-principle: <em>The simplest choice should be the correct
                choice.</em>
            </p>
            <br/>
            <br/>
            <p> The decisions you make early in a project should not come back later to haunt you. </p>
            <p> We have found that a component approach to web development is the best way of realizing these
                principles. Structuring the framework and your application around components makes it possible to move
                all the boring plumbing code out of your application and into the framework. You write less code, you
                write simpler code, sometimes you write <em>no</em> code. HiveMind picks up the slack. </p>
        </section>

        <section name="Third Party Components">

            <p> Additional libraries of HiveMind components by third parties. </p>

            <table>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://beanform.sourceforge.net">BeanForm</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> All-in-one, flexible bean editor. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://sotacs.sourceforge.net/home/index.html">Sotacs</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        <strong>So</strong>me more <strong>Ta</strong>pestry <strong>C</strong>omponent<strong>s</strong>, including menus,
                        Ajax text fields and dynamic images
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://tacos.sourceforge.net">Tacos</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Suite of Ajax-enabled components. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://hivemind-jsmenu.sourceforge.net">HiveMind Menu Component</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> HiveMind version of <a href="http://jscook.sourceforge.net/JSCookMenu/">JSCookMenu</a>. </td>
                </tr>
    
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://tapfx.sourceforge.net/">TapFX</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> A set of dynamic, skinnable, DHTML enabled, client-side state preserving web components. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://equalitylearning.org/Tassel/app">
                            Tassel
                        </a>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        HiveMind Searchable Selection of Components -- Searchable index of HiveMind components
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>

        <section name="HiveMind Extensions">

            <p> This section lists common HiveMind extensions that have been created by third parties. </p>

            <table>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://raibledesigns.com/wiki/Wiki.jsp?page=AppFuse">AppFuse</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> "Kickstart" application development that pre-integrates HiveMind with Spring, Hibernate and
                        several other libraries. </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://www.thelabllc.com">Cognition</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Eclipse plugin that enables graphical creation of database-driven HiveMind applications. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://honeycomb.javaforge.com/">Honeycomb</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Hibernate integration, supports transaction-per-request and transaction-per-conversation. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://files.doublenegative.com.au/jumpstart/">Jumpstart</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                        Like AppFuse, but specific to HiveMind: a CRUD application outline waiting to be filled in with
                        your own domain classes
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://howardlewisship.com/hivemind-javaforge/hivemind-spring/">hivemind-spring</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>Easy integration with Spring; inject Spring beans directly into pages.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://www.erinors.com/product/tapdoc/">TapDoc</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>Generate component documentation automatically.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://www.carmanconsulting.com/tapernate">Tapernate</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Hibernate integration; manages transactions and persistent entity objects. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://www.carmanconsulting.com/hivemind-acegi">hivemind-acegi</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Integration with the <a href="http://www.acegisecurity.org/">Acegi</a> security framework.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://howardlewisship.com/hivemind-javaforge/hivemind-flash/">hivemind-flash</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Short term property storage modelled on Rail's "flash". </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://howardlewisship.com/hivemind-javaforge/hivemind-prop/">hivemind-prop</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Non-reflective property access; fast but limited replacement for "ognl:". </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://howardlewisship.com/hivemind-javaforge/hivemind-testng/">hivemind-testng</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Base classes for testing HiveMind components with JDK 1.5. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <strong>
                            <a href="http://www.trailsframework.org/">Trails</a>
                        </strong>
                    </td>
                    <td> Domain driven application development environment, modeled on Rails and Naked Objects. </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>

        <section name="IDE Integration">

            <p> These open-source, third party extensions allow you to more easily develop your HiveMind applications
                using popular IDEs. </p>

            <table>
                <tr>
                    <td> Eclipse </td>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://www.thelabllc.com">Cognition</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Visual builder for database applications, driven by database object model. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td/>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://ezingbuilder.sourceforge.net/cms/">eZing Builder</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Visual editor for HTML with HiveMind extensions. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td/>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://spindle.sourceforge.net">Spindle</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Integrated editting and simple refactoring. Stable version is HiveMind 3 only. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td/>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://hivemindpalette.sourceforge.net">Palette</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Extends Spindle with palette-based drag and drop editting. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>IDEA</td>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://tapidea.javaforge.com">TapIDEA</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>Based on part of the Spindle code base.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td/>
                    <td><a href="http://handyedit.com/index.html">HandyHiveMind</a></td>
                    <td>
                        Helpful completions and navigations in the HTML template, and a Create HiveMind component wizard.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>NetBeans</td>
                    <td>
                        <a href="https://nbhivemindsupport.dev.java.net/">nbhivemindsupport</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>Wizards for creating new HiveMind files and elements within files.</td>
                </tr>
            </table>

        </section>
    </body>
</document>
