<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Welcome to HiveMind</title>
        <author email="ahuegen@apache.org">Achim Huegen</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Welcome to HiveMind 2">

            <div id="downloadbox">
                <h5>Get HiveMind 1.1.1</h5>
                <p>
                    <a href="download.html">
                        <img valign="top" src="images/folder-open.gif" border="0" alt="" title="download"/> Download
                    </a> HiveMind 1.1.1 </p>

                <br/>
                
                <h5>Get HiveMind 2.0-alpha-1</h5>
                <p>
                    <a href="download.html">
                        <img valign="top" src="images/folder-open.gif" border="0" alt="" title="download"/> Download
                    </a> HiveMind 2.0-alpha-1 </p>

                <br/>

                <!-- Leave the last few news items here -->

                <h5>New!</h5>
                <ul style="list-style:none">
                    <li><a href="news.html#First alpha release of HiveMind 2">First alpha release of HiveMind 2</a></li>
                    <li><a href="news.html#New Site">New Site</a></li>
                    <li><a href="news.html#HiveMind - Now Top Level">HiveMind - Now Top Level Project</a></li>
                </ul>
                
            </div>
            <p><strong>HiveMind</strong> is an services and configuration microkernel.
             Its features are also referred to as Inversion of Control (IoC) Container
             or Lightweight Container.</p>
             <p>The adoption of HiveMind in an application ensures the use of 
             certain design principles which improve encapsulation, modularization,
             testability and reusability.</p>
						 <ul>
								<li><strong>Services</strong>: HiveMind
									services are <em>POJOs</em> (Plain Old Java Objects) that can be easily
									accessed and combined. Each service ideally defines a Java interface it
									implements (this is not mandatory). HiveMind takes care of the life cycle
									of services.  It instantiates and finalizes services and configures each
									service just as necessary. HiveMind lets services collaborate with each
									other via dependency injection, so that the service code itself
									is released from the task of looking up dependencies.</li>
								<li> <strong>Configuration</strong>: 
									HiveMind allows you to provide complex configuration data to your
									services in a format <em>you</em> define. HiveMind will integrate the
									contributions of such data from multiple modules and convert it all into
									data objects for you. HiveMind configurations allow for powerful,
									data-driven solutions which combine seemlessly with the service
									architecture.</li>
							</ul>
        </section>

        <section name="Related projects and HiveMind Extensions">

            <p> This section lists related projects and HiveMind extensions that have been created by third parties. </p>

            <table>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://tapestry.apache.org">Tapestry</a>
                    </td>
                    <td> Web framework that uses HiveMind under the covers. </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://hivetranse.sourceforge.net">HiveMind Utilities</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>
                       Repository of HiveMind extensions for the support of transaction handling, security, remoting, events and rich clients.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://crispy.sourceforge.net">Crispy</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>Client for Remote Invocation for different kinds of services via proxies.
                       Offers an extension for the invocation of HiveMind services.</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <a href="http://mule.codehaus.org">Mule</a>
                    </td>
                    <td>Enterprise Service Bus (ESB) messaging framework that supports HiveMind as object container.</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>
